<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Handmade Oasis</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Handmade Oasis</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2025, Ramtin Javanmardi.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 23:15:26 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Brain Dump: AI Assisted Workflows</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/brain-dump-ai-assisted-workflows/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 23:15:26 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/brain-dump-ai-assisted-workflows/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is just like a note or dump of everything I research on AI agents, MCP, and&#xA;other generative AI stuff. I think the correct phrase for it is a stream of&#xA;consciousness dump&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There seems to be a kind of tier or ladder of sophistication that is slowly&#xA;getting shaped when it comes to AI assisted workflows, especially in relation to&#xA;software engineering. As I see it currently we have the use of online chat&#xA;interfaces, this is where you have chatGPT, Claude and company. At this point 3 years in,&#xA;this I think we have to admit has become table stakes pretty much. The next&#xA;level up is having an agent side by side your daily work. Here you have direct&#xA;access to the LLM and if you use a vscode fork like Cursor or any of their&#xA;competitors its usually just another pane on the right side of your code. This&#xA;is pretty nice, especially when you start to use it. It just feels so nice to&#xA;not have to leave your editor (personally i hated having to use these vs code&#xA;forks, and so glad the next level now exists), and just have the LLM have some&#xA;context around your code and so on.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Linux&#39;s Birthday and My Journey With It</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/linux-birthday-and-my-journey-with-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2025 12:08:40 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/linux-birthday-and-my-journey-with-it/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Let me preface this post with the fact that&#xA;I was a huge macOS fanboy for a decade or so and only started feeling that the&#xA;OS was getting in my way a couple of years ago.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With today being the 34th birthday of Linux it made me reflect a bit on how I&#xA;have used it over the years. I started out using Ubuntu at University 12 years&#xA;ago for some intro labs and for learning how to navigate the filesystem with a&#xA;terminal. That experience was very meh, I thought the OS looked clunky and I was&#xA;not sold on using the terminal over a GUI, especially when compared to the sleek&#xA;and beautiful macOS UI. So this was an opinion that I held on to for a long&#xA;time, of course I was using Linux in the cloud for servers and even just running&#xA;stuff with docker and so on but that was it really.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/aboutme/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/aboutme/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;about-me&#34;&gt;About Me&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hi, I&amp;rsquo;m Ramtin Javanmardi!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to my corner of the internet where I share my thoughts and experiences on:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data Engineering&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Developer Tooling&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Low level programming&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Game and graphics programming&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;General Technology&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My guiding principle when it comes to engineering is: Always aim for great, not&#xA;good enough, not good and definitely not perfect.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I studied Computer Science at university and spent the last two years&#xA;specializing in machine learning. Started out as a web developer for a very&#xA;short time but switched into data engineering almost immediately, and have been&#xA;doing that ever since. Currently, I work as the lead data platform&#xA;engineer at a scale-up in Stockholm.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
