<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Stream of Consciousness on Handmade Oasis</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tag/stream-of-consciousness/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Stream of Consciousness on Handmade Oasis</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2025, Ramtin Javanmardi.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2025 21:05:43 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tag/stream-of-consciousness/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>AI and Software Engineering, the Conflict Within</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ai-and-software-engineering-the-conflict-within/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2025 21:05:43 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ai-and-software-engineering-the-conflict-within/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I wrote a post a while ago about &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/brain-dump-ai-assisted-workflows/&#34;&gt;my current workflow when working with AI&lt;/a&gt;, my&#xA;initial skepticism and some brief mentions of the concept of recreational&#xA;programming. This post is going to be a continuation of the train of thought&#xA;presented in that previous post, but it will be a stand alone piece still. In&#xA;other words there is no need to have read the previous one to follow along in&#xA;this post.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Brain Dump: AI Assisted Workflows</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/brain-dump-ai-assisted-workflows/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 23:15:26 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/brain-dump-ai-assisted-workflows/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is just like a note or dump of everything I research on AI agents, MCP, and&#xA;other generative AI stuff. I think the correct phrase for it is a stream of&#xA;consciousness dump&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There seems to be a kind of tier or ladder of sophistication that is slowly&#xA;getting shaped when it comes to AI assisted workflows, especially in relation to&#xA;software engineering. As I see it currently we have the use of online chat&#xA;interfaces, this is where you have chatGPT, Claude and company. At this point 3 years in,&#xA;this I think we have to admit has become table stakes pretty much. The next&#xA;level up is having an agent side by side your daily work. Here you have direct&#xA;access to the LLM and if you use a vscode fork like Cursor or any of their&#xA;competitors its usually just another pane on the right side of your code. This&#xA;is pretty nice, especially when you start to use it. It just feels so nice to&#xA;not have to leave your editor (personally i hated having to use these vs code&#xA;forks, and so glad the next level now exists), and just have the LLM have some&#xA;context around your code and so on.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
